William D. Dowling Papers
William D. Dowling Papers
1961-1980
1965-1978
Dowling, William D.
0.5 linear ft.
Papers include published materials, speeches, memoranda, agendas, notes, correspondence, outlines and lists. There are some papers from Dowling’s work on the Ad Hoc Committee on Administration of the Subcommittee for Adult Students at Ohio State University. Many of the papers reflect his interest in adult basic education and vocational and technical training for adults.
149437
Biographical History
William Dowling was on the faculty of Ohio State University in the College of Education. He served as chairman of the Ad Hoc Committee on Administration of the Subcommittee for Adult Students. He was also active in national organizations such as the Commission of Professors of Adult Education (CPAE). His interests include adult basic education and vocational and technical education for adults.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The material - published material, speeches, memoranda, agendas, notes, correspondence, outlines and lists - generally representing the period 1965-78, is arranged alphabetically. A number of pamphlets have been removed to the adult education pamphlet file.
Related Material
The library holds a considerable number of collections related to adult and continuing education. Please refer to for a complete listing.
Commision of Professors of Adult Education (CPAE)
Hendrickson, Andrew
Subject and Genre Headings
Adult education; Dowling, William D.; Hendrickson, Andrew, b. 1899.; Commission of Professors of Adult Education.; Adult education.; Agendas (administrative records); Correspondence.; Memorandums.; Speeches (documents); Educators.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Inventory
- Correspondence-subject files
  - Conference on University Education Related to Aging, 26 Mar 1965 (Box 1)
  - Commission of Professors of Adult Education
    - Presentation by Dowling, 30 Oct 1973 (Box 1)
    - Presentation by M.J.Even, 5 Nov 1979 (Box 1)
  - "Effective Reading in Green Bay" by Dowling, 1961 (Box 1)
  - National Institute for Resource Development and Utilization in ABE, 6-17 Apr 1970 (Box 1)
  - Ohio State University (OSU)
    - Ad Hoc Committee on Adult Students, Art Adams, 1978 (Box 1)
    - Center for Vocational and Technical Education (Box 1)
      - "Developmental Program Goals", 1972; 1975
      - Robert Taylor, 1973
    - College of Education, misc., 1972; 1980 (Box 1)
    - Graduate Course Outline, Vocational-Technical Education, undated (Box 1)
    - Hendrickson, Andrew, 1963-1964 (Box 1)
    - Publications, 1967; 1975 (Box 1)